Back, back, back, back! Eat salt, jerks!
뒤로, 뒤로, 뒤로, 뒤로! 소금을 먹어라, 멍청아!
Take that!
가져가세요!
It took it.
걸렸습니다.
Sorry, guy, all out of backpacks!
미안해요, 배낭이 다 떨어졌어요!
Get away from him, you mouth breather!
그 사람에게서 떨어져요, 입으로 숨쉬는 사람!
Um, should we help her?
음, 우리가 그녀를 도와야 할까요?
After the day she's had, I'd say let her have this one.
그녀가 보낸 하루 이후, 나는 그녀에게 이것을 갖게 해주고 싶습니다.
What? No spores?
무엇? 포자가 없나요?
You okay?
괜찮아?
I think Dan might ban me for life.
댄이 저를 평생 금지할 수도 있을 것 같아요.
We have bigger problems than the Food Mart, Dustin.
우리에겐 더 큰 문제가 있다 푸드마트보다, 더스틴.
Way bigger.
훨씬 더 커요.
Geez, worst storm damage we've had in years.
이런, 최악의 폭풍 피해 우리는 몇 년 동안 그랬어요.
It was a wild one, Chief. Hope this place is insured.
정말 대단한 일이었습니다, 국장님. 이 장소가 보험에 가입되기를 바랍니다.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
오, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼!
You're not done yet?
아직 끝나지 않았나요?
You traded turns for Erica's dessert again, didn't you?
당신은 차례를 교환했습니다 또 에리카의 디저트로, 그렇지?
Yeah, last week
응, 지난주에
before I knew we'd be saving this town from crazy creatures, again!
우리가 이 마을을 구할 것이라는 걸 알기도 전에 미친 생물들로부터 다시!
My parents should be throwing me a parade, not forcing me to shovel snow!
내 부모님이 나에게 퍼레이드를 열어줘야 하는데, 나에게 눈을 치우라고 강요하지 마세요!
You're shoveling something, all right.
뭔가를 삽질하고 있는군요.
Come on, town hero!
자, 마을 영웅이여!
Hey, what's going on?
무슨 일이야?
My bike's gotta be around here somewhere.
내 자전거가 이 근처 어딘가에 있을 거에요.
Hold on.
기다리다.
U-turn! U-turn!
유턴! 유턴!
Are you sure this time?
이번엔 확실해?
He was sure the last three times.
그는 지난 세 번 확신했다.
Yeah, yeah. Sorry I'm not an expert
응, 응. 미안 난 전문가가 아니야
at finding something lost in a historic blizzard.
잃어버린 것을 찾으면서 역사적인 눈보라 속에서.
Why were you out in the snow anyway?
그런데 왜 눈 속에 있었나요?
I thought you were just going to hit the arcade.
나는 생각했다 넌 그냥 아케이드에 들어가려고 했어.
- He was on a date. - With Rosario.
- 그 사람 데이트 중이었어. - 로사리오와 함께.
Would you clowns give it a rest? Yes, fine. I was with Rosario,
광대들아 좀 쉬게 해줄래? 응, 알았어. 난 로사리오와 함께 있었어
but we were working the H.I.C. case.
하지만 우리는 H.I.C에서 일하고 있었습니다. 사례.
Dustin, why are you red?
더스틴, 왜 빨간색이야?
It's...
그건...
I'm not! I'm...
나는 그렇지 않다! 나는...
My bike!
내 자전거!
And you all doubted me.
그리고 당신은 모두 나를 의심했습니다.
He's changing the subject.
그는 주제를 바꾸고 있습니다.
No. I'm simply trying to keep us focused on the task at hand.
아니요. 저는 단지 우리가 집중하도록 하려는 것뿐입니다. 현재 작업에.
Rosario saw the same blinking light Charlie did
로사리오는 똑같은 깜박이는 빛을 보았습니다 찰리는 그랬어
after she played host to that Jerk O'Lantern thing.
그녀가 호스트 역할을 한 후 Jerk O'Lantern 같은 것 말이죠.
You seriously think that's a coincidence?
진심으로 그게 우연이라고 생각하시나요?
Charlie and Rosario were possessed by totally different creatures.
찰리와 로사리오는 빙의되었습니다 완전히 다른 생물에 의해.
Those creatures share a common ancestor.
그 생물들은 공통 조상을 공유합니다.
Like... Hordak.
마치... 호닥.
Hord-what?
호드-뭐?
Is that a She-Ra reference?
쉬라 언급인가요?
Yep. Hordak, like controls the Horde.
네. Hordak은 호드를 통제하는 것과 같습니다.
The biggest baddie of all the baddies.
악당중 가장 큰 악당.
Except for his boss, Horde Prime, of course.
그의 상사를 제외하고, 물론 호드 프라임이죠.
Okay. Let me try to explain this a way that's less cool.
좋아요. 이것을 설명해보겠다. 덜 멋진 방법입니다.
Think of a beehive and the queen bee.
벌집과 여왕벌을 생각해 보세요.
The creatures that possessed Charlie and Rosario,
생물들 찰리와 로사리오를 소유한
they could've all descended from the same Queen
그들 모두 내려갔을 수도 있었어 같은 여왕에게서
and shared her memories. That's why they had the same vision.
그리고 추억을 공유했다. 그렇기 때문에 그들은 같은 비전을 갖고 있었습니다.
So the vision didn't come from them.
그러므로 비전은 그들에게서 나온 것이 아닙니다.
It came from the Queen.
여왕님에게서 왔습니다.
Exactly.
정확히.
If we figure out where the light is Charlie and Rosario saw,
빛이 어디에 있는지 알아낸다면 Charlie와 Rosario는
then we'll locate the source of all these creatures.
그럼 출처를 찾아보겠습니다 이 모든 생물 중.
Hordak.
호르닥.
We know the creatures are in the sewers.
우리는 그 생물들이 하수구에 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
If there's a queen like you say, that's where we gotta start.
당신 같은 여왕이 있다면, 그것이 바로 우리가 시작해야 할 곳입니다.
If you'd rather embark on a wild goose chase
차라리 승선하고 싶다면 거위를 쫓는 중
in the stinkiest depths of Hawkins,
호킨스의 가장 악취나는 깊은 곳에서,
instead of systematically triangulating the Queen's location
체계적으로 삼각측량을 하기보다는 여왕의 위치
using logic and science, then--
논리와 과학을 사용하면--
I'm tired of being chased.
쫓기느라 지쳤어요.
We should do the chasing.
우리는 추적을 해야 합니다.
Fine.
괜찮은.
Well, if we're headed underground for a monster beatdown,
글쎄, 우리가 지하로 향하고 있다면 괴물을 쓰러뜨리려면
we're gonna need some gear.
장비가 좀 필요해요.
And that just so happens to be my specialty.
그리고 그런 일이 실제로 일어난다 내 특기가 되려고.
Whoa.
와.
Welcome to...
오신 것을 환영합니다...
The mosh pit!
모쉬 구덩이!
Whoa!
와!
This is like Nikola Tesla meets Dr. Frankenstein.
니콜라테슬라같네 프랑켄슈타인 박사를 만납니다.
You made all of this?
이걸 다 네가 만든 거야?
Uh, yep. And if anything's gonna stop that Queen, it's gonna be here.
어, 응. 그리고 뭔가가 멈출 것 같으면 그 여왕님, 여기 있을 거예요.
Gear up, Terminators.
준비하세요, 터미네이터 여러분.
This stuff is sick, Nikki.
이건 정말 역겹다, 니키.
Sick as in cool, but also sick as in kinda sick.
시원할 때처럼 아프고, 하지만 좀 아픈 것처럼 아프기도 해요.
- Ah!
- 아!
Uh, sorry?
어, 미안?
Well, that ball had it coming.
글쎄, 그 공이 오고 있었어.
Hey!
여기요!
Made something for you too.
당신을 위해서도 뭔가를 만들었습니다.
No way! Is this the mallet from the festival?
안 돼요! 이게 페스티벌에 나온 망치인가요?
With one or two bonuses.
하나 또는 두 개의 보너스가 있습니다.
Nikki, this is so cool. Thank you.
니키, 이거 정말 멋지다. 감사합니다.
It's like you can see into my brain and make my dreams real!
마치 내 뇌를 들여다볼 수 있는 것 같아 그리고 내 꿈을 현실로 만들어주세요!
What do you call this beauty?
이 아름다움을 뭐라고 부르나요?
Uh, you name it.
어, 이름을 정하세요.
I'd like to officially make you
공식적으로 당신을 만들고 싶습니다
the H.I.C.'s Head of R&D for Field Technologies.
H.I.C.의 R&D 책임자 필드 기술용.
Whoa! Sounds rad. Count me in.
와! 정말 대단한 것 같아요. 나를 포함해 주세요.
Oh! Oh my goodness, Nikki! Uh, you have guests.
오! 맙소사, 니키! 아, 손님이 계시군요.
- Hi, Mrs. Baxter!
- 안녕하세요, 백스터 부인!
Hi, Mrs. Baxter!
안녕하세요, 백스터 부인!
Hey! Hello, kids. Checkin' out Nikki's knickknacks?
여기요! 안녕, 얘들아. 니키의 장식품을 살펴보시나요?
Mom, don't call them that, because then the name will stick.
엄마, 그렇게 부르지 마세요 그러면 이름이 붙을 것이기 때문입니다.
I'm so sorry. I thought you and them...
정말 죄송해요. 내 생각에는 당신과 그 사람들이...
We're cool now.
이제 괜찮아요.
Really? Okay. Good, good, good. Then...
정말? 좋아요. 좋아, 좋아, 좋아. 그럼...
I didn't mean to interrupt, but I wanted to give you something.
방해할 생각은 아니었는데, 하지만 난 당신에게 뭔가를 주고 싶었어요.
Thanks, Mom. Love you.
고마워요, 엄마. 사랑해요.
Oh, I love you too, sweet girl.
아, 나도 사랑해요, 귀여운 아가씨.
Happy birthday.
생일 축하해요.
- It's your birthday? - Birthday? What?!
- 생일이에요? - 생일? 무엇?!
Uh, I... I'm just gonna...
어, 난... 난 그냥...
I... I'm gonna go, I guess.
나... 갈 것 같아요.
Traitor.
배신자.
Why didn't you tell us?
왜 우리에게 말하지 않았나요?
I guess I'm not really a birthday person.
아무래도 나는 생일을 맞는 사람은 아닌 것 같다.
Besides, who would I invite? My mom?
게다가 누구를 초대할까요? 우리 엄마?
How about us?
우리는 어때요?
Okay. Um...
좋아요. 음...
Yeah. Maybe this year I'd be up for trying something different.
응. 어쩌면 올해 나는 다른 것을 시도해 볼 것입니다.
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
But first, we got some sewer business to take care of.
하지만 먼저 하수도 사업을 시작했어 돌보기 위해.
Light 'em up.
불을 켜세요.
So...
그럼...
Does this mean that the sewers are our official date spot?
하수구라는 뜻인가요? 우리 공식 데이트 장소야?
Don't make me puke.
나를 토하게 만들지 마세요.
You don't wanna celebrate our anniversary here?
넌 축하하고 싶지 않잖아 여기서 우리 기념일이요?
I could bring candles.
양초를 가져올 수도 있어요.
Gross.
역겨운.
You have really never had a birthday party?
넌 정말 한 번도 그런 적이 없었어 생일 파티?
I have never had one either.
나도 한번도 가져본 적이 없습니다.
Is that 'cause of where you grew up?
그게 당신이 자란 곳 때문인가요?
No one ever mentioned birthdays in the lab.
아무도 생일에 대해 언급한 적이 없습니다. 실험실에서.
I did not even know when mine was until a few months ago.
내 것이 언제인지도 몰랐다 몇 달 전까지만 해도.
They really kept you locked down, huh?
그들은 정말 당신을 가두어 두었어요, 그렇죠?
Locked down? Yes.
잠겨 있나요? 예.
But you went all over?
그런데 다 갔나요?
So many places. They all kind of just blur together.
너무 많은 곳. 그것들은 모두 함께 흐릿해집니다.
My mom tried to make sure I did regular kid stuff,
엄마는 확실히 하려고 노력했어 난 평범한 아이들과 관련된 일을 했어
like the mall and karate class,
쇼핑몰이나 가라테 수업처럼
but we could never really crack birthday parties.
하지만 우리는 절대 무너질 수 없어 생일 파티.
I guess they're just a little too normal for someone like me.
내 생각엔 그 사람들이 좀 너무 평범한 것 같아 나 같은 사람을 위해.
I am not normal either.
나도 정상은 아니다.
Well, who wants to be normal anyway, huh?
글쎄, 어쨌든 평범해지고 싶은 사람이 어디 있겠나?
Whoa. Guys, are you seeing these?
와. 여러분, 이거 보고 있나요?
What do they mean?
무슨 뜻인가요?
I think it means--
제 생각에는...
I think it means we go this way.
내 생각엔 우리가 이쪽으로 간다는 뜻인 것 같아.
We must be getting close.
우리는 가까워지고 있는 게 틀림없어요.
Who, uh...
누구, 어...
Who wants to go first?
누가 먼저 가고 싶어?
Fine.
괜찮은.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
A little late for that, stalker.
그러기에는 조금 늦었어요, 스토커님.
These vines are strong enough to break through cement.
이 덩굴은 충분히 강하다 시멘트를 뚫기 위해서다.
- If this whole place is riddled with them... - We have to be careful where we step.
- 온 동네가 그들로 가득 차 있다면... - 우리는 발걸음을 조심해야 합니다.
Max?
맥스?
Max!
맥스!
You're gonna want to see this.
당신은 이것을보고 싶어 할 것입니다.
End of the line.
줄 끝.
Look!
바라보다!
Only one of them.
그 중 하나만.
- We can handle-- - No.
- 우리가 처리할 수 있는 건-- - 아니요.
She's right.
그녀 말이 맞아요.
If we fight them, we'll alert everything in the sewer system we're here.
그들과 싸우면 우리는 모든 것을 경고할 것이다 하수구에 우리가 있어요.
Those things could come back around any second.
그런 것들은 그럴 수도 있지 잠시 후에 다시 오세요.
We gotta figure out a way to get over there
우린 방법을 찾아야 해 거기로 가려면
without having to climb down into the death tunnel first.
올라가지 않고도 먼저 죽음의 터널로 내려가세요.
Oh, silly me. I left my grappling hook in my other pants.
아, 바보같아. 갈고리를 버렸어요 내 다른 바지에.
I didn't.
나는하지 않았다.
Who's ready for a ride?
탈 준비가 된 사람은 누구입니까?
Steady. Steady.
꾸준한. 꾸준한.
- Come on! Hurry! - Hurry up!
- 어서 해봐요! 서두르다! - 서둘러요!
What are you waiting for?
당신은 무엇을 기다리고 있습니까?
Uh, guys?
어, 얘들아?
Yes! Yes! Go, El!
예! 예! 가, 엘!
Ow.
아야.
Where the heck are we now?
우리는 지금 어디에 있는 걸까요?
Sewer Junction.
하수구 교차점.
Gross!
역겨운!
- Ugh. - Check this out.
- 어. - 이것 좀 보세요.
Don't get too close! That's a power transformer.
너무 가까이 가지 마세요! 그것은 전력 변압기입니다.
It'll pack a lethal zap if you mess with it wrong.
치명적인 충격을 줄 거예요 잘못 다루면.
Who just leaves their tools lying around?
누가 도구를 그냥 방치해 두나요?
Probably someone who didn't have much of a choice.
아마도 누군가 선택의 여지가 별로 없었던 사람.
Dustin.
더스틴.
- Dustin! - Ah!
- 더스틴! - 아!
Get back!
돌아가세요!
Knickknacks at the ready!
잡화 준비 완료!
Please do not call them that.
그렇게 부르지 마세요.
She sends out an aroma Of undefined love
그녀는 향기를 내보낸다 정의되지 않은 사랑의
It drips on down in a mist from above
위에서 안개 속에서 아래로 떨어진다
She's just the girl
그 사람은 그냥 그런 여자야
Whoa!
와!
You're tangling with the wrong guy! Taste my Wizard's Breath!
당신은 엉뚱한 남자와 엉키고 있어요! 내 마법사의 숨결을 맛보세요!
Whoa!
와!
Incoming!
들어오는!
She's just the girl The girl you want
그 사람은 그냥 그런 여자야 당신이 원하는 여자
She's just the girl, she's just the girl
그녀는 단지 소녀일 뿐이야, 그녀는 단지 소녀일 뿐이야
Ah!
아!
Look at you with your mouth watering
군침이 도는 당신을 보세요
Look at you with your mind spinnin'
생각이 돌고 있는 당신을 바라보세요'
Not good.
좋지 않다.
She's just the girl you want
그녀는 당신이 원하는 바로 그 여자입니다
She's just the girl, she's just the girl The girl you want
그녀는 단지 소녀일 뿐이야, 그녀는 단지 소녀일 뿐이야 당신이 원하는 여자
Is that all you got, you dumb hedge?
당신이 가진 건 그게 전부야, 이 멍청한 울타리야?
She's just the girl The girl you want
그 사람은 그냥 그런 여자야 당신이 원하는 여자
Eyes! Eyes! Cover your eyes!
눈! 눈! 눈을 감으세요!
Oh, my...
이런...
That was a close one.
그것은 가까운 일이었습니다.
I think I have some sewer stuff in my mouth.
하수구 같은 게 있는 것 같아 내 입에.
Geared up or not, we weren't ready for that.
준비가 되었든 아니든, 우리는 그럴 준비가 되어 있지 않았습니다.
Come on, guys. We can't stop now. We're so close. We just have to--
어서, 얘들아. 우리는 지금 멈출 수 없습니다. 우리는 너무 가깝습니다. 우리는 그냥--
Leave before we die?
죽기 전에 떠나요?
Everyone, grab your stuff. We're getting out of here.
여러분, 물건을 챙기세요. 우리는 여기서 나갈거야.
Now!
지금!
That was a total disaster.
그것은 완전한 재앙이었습니다.
Guys, I'm starting to think we finally met our match.
얘들아, 나 이제 생각이 나기 시작했어 드디어 우리 짝을 만났습니다.
There is no part of me that doesn't hurt.
아프지 않은 부분이 없어요.
There's no part of me that doesn't stink.
내 몸에서 냄새가 나지 않는 부분은 없습니다.
My shoes are never going to be the same.
내 신발은 결코 예전과 같지 않을 것이다.
That was not a success.
그것은 성공하지 못했습니다.
Yeah. I'm sorry, Nikki.
응. 미안해요, 니키.
This is pretty much the worst birthday ever, huh?
이건 꽤 많은데 최악의 생일이었어, 응?
No way, Zombie Boy. This was the best birthday of all time.
안 돼, 좀비 보이. 이번 생일은 역대 최고의 생일이었습니다.
How?
어떻게?
Number one, friends. That's kind of a new thing for me.
첫 번째, 친구들. 그것은 나에게 일종의 새로운 것입니다.
Two, dangerous adventures in a sewer.
두 번째, 하수구에서의 위험한 모험.
Disgusting, but way more exciting than Chuck E. Cheese.
역겹지만 훨씬 더 흥미진진하다 척 E. 치즈보다.
And three,
그리고 세 번째,
party's not over, class.
파티는 끝나지 않았어, 수업.
Nice. We should've baked a cake.
멋진. 우리는 케이크를 구웠어야 했어요.
I'll see your cake and raise you.
네 케이크 보고 키워줄게.
The fresh snack with the snack in the middle.
신선한 스낵 중간에 간식이 있어요.
Stocked up before the Food Mart imploded.
푸드마트가 붕괴되기 전에 비축해 두었습니다.
- Nice. - I'll take one!
- 멋진. - 하나 가져갈게요!
Here you go.
여기요.
It's your birthday too.
당신 생일이기도 해요.
Yeah, those are my favorite.
응, 그거 내가 제일 좋아하는 거야.
But it's not.
하지만 그렇지 않습니다.
Well, you missed like 13 of them in a row. It's time to start making them up.
글쎄요, 연속으로 13개 정도를 놓쳤군요. 이제 그것들을 만들기 시작할 시간입니다.
- Happy birthday to you
- 생일 축하합니다
Happy birthday, El and Nikki
생일 축하해요, 엘과 니키
Head of R&D for H.I.C.
H.I.C. R&D 책임자
Happy birthday to you
생일 축하합니다
You know you're supposed to make a wish, right?
알잖아 소원을 빌어야지, 그렇지?
I did.
그랬어요.
It already came true.
그것은 이미 실현되었습니다.
Aw!
아!
I wished I could figure out how to hurt the Queen,
내가 알아낼 수 있었으면 좋았을 텐데 여왕을 다치게 하는 방법
and I think I have an idea.
내 생각엔 좋은 생각이 있는 것 같아.
How?
어떻게?
Light.
빛.
My mom's always talking about how crazy sensitive plants are to light.
우리 엄마는 항상 얘기해요. 식물이 빛에 얼마나 민감한지.
Like if they don't get enough, then they die?
마치 그들이 충분히 얻지 못하는 것처럼, 그럼 그 사람들은 죽나요?
Exactly.
정확히.
But those vines live in the sewers.
하지만 그 덩굴은 하수구에 산다.
They're doing just fine, and there's no light down there.
그들은 잘 지내고 있어요. 그리고 거기에는 빛이 없습니다.
Yeah, well, that's because the opposite's also true with plants.
응, 뭐, 그렇기 때문이야 식물의 경우에도 그 반대가 적용됩니다.
Too much light?
빛이 너무 많나요?
It's not gonna be easy.
쉽지 않을 거예요.
Replicating the lumens generated by that transformer won't be possible
생성된 루멘 복제 그 변압기로는 불가능해
without some serious juice.
진지한 주스없이.
Hey, if anyone can figure out how to replicate the lumens
야, 누가 알아낼 수 있다면 루멘을 복제하는 방법
to make a butt-kicking weapon, it's gonna be you.
엉덩이를 차는 무기를 만들려면 바로 당신일 거예요.
Darn straight, Zombie Boy.
똑바로 해라, 좀비 보이.
Mike, hand me that 14-gauge copper.
마이크, 그 14게이지 구리를 나한테 건네줘.
Pliers. Pliers.
펜치. 펜치.
Whoa.
와.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Okay, okay, okay. This is all so awesome for sure,
알았어, 알았어, 알았어. 정말 정말 멋진 일이네요,
but I got a little emergency to deal with first.
그런데 좀 긴급 상황이 생겼어 먼저 처리할 것.
Building gear makes me have to go pee.
장비를 만들다 보니 소변을 보러 가야 합니다.
You waiting for permission?
허가를 기다리고 있나요?
Your experiment?
당신의 실험?
That's what you're worried about?
그게 걱정되는 거야?
The storm just wiped out my only source of income.
폭풍이 막 휩쓸고 지나갔어 나의 유일한 수입원.
- That's not the point. - I don't think you understand.
- 그게 요점이 아니야. - 내 생각엔 당신이 이해하지 못하는 것 같아요.
No, no, no, no, no. That's the problem. I do understand.
아니, 아니, 아니, 아니, 아니. 그게 문제입니다. 나는 이해한다.
I understand this wasn't part of the plan.
나는 이것이 계획의 일부가 아니라는 것을 이해합니다.
Don't make me do something I will regret.
내가 후회할 일을 하게 만들지 마세요.
Um...
음...
Bathroom?
화장실?
Oh! Hey!
오! 여기요!
Sure, sure, sure, sure. It's upstairs, second door on the right.
물론이죠, 물론이죠, 물론이죠. 위층에 있고 오른쪽에서 두 번째 문입니다.
Happy birthday to you
생일 축하합니다
Happy birthday to me
생일 축하해요
It's not your birthday, Dustin.
오늘은 네 생일이 아니야, 더스틴.
Happy birthday to you
생일 축하합니다
Oh!
오!
Evolution is the process
진화는 과정이다
by which an organism adapts into an enhanced version of itself.
유기체가 적응하는 과정 그 자체로 향상된 버전이 됩니다.
I could talk about this stuff all day.
하루종일 이 얘기만 할 수도 있겠네요.
Evolution, extinction, especially extinction.
진화, 멸종, 특히 멸종.
The fear of extinction is a great motivator.
멸종에 대한 두려움 훌륭한 동기 부여자입니다.
Like mushrooms and pine trees. When they're dying, they release spores.
버섯과 소나무처럼요. 죽을 때 포자를 방출합니다.
These spores are gonna ensure the survival of their species.
이 포자는 다음을 보장합니다. 종족의 생존.
Oh no.
안 돼.
Mrs. Baxter is Horde Prime.
백스터 부인은 호드 프라임입니다.